<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <!-- We used a letter template for this one. My only question would be what publication information would be important in a letter like this. -->
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
               <title type="main">H.H. Horn Letter from Hitoshi Motoshima</title>
               <author>Hitoshi Moshima<ref target="#n01"/></author>
               <editor xml:id="bb">Cooper Rohde</editor>
               <editor xml:id="ow">Malik Rasaq</editor>
               <editor xml:id="jg">Jeffrey Gilbert</editor>

            <respStmt>
               <resp>Encoded by,</resp>
               <persName>Cooper Rohde</persName>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>

         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>
               <orgName></orgName>
            </publisher>
            <date></date>
            <availability>
               <p>This file is free to download, share, or repurpose for educational and project development purposes.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>A letter to L.L Horn, by the mayor of Nagasaki</p>
            <bibl> </bibl>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <repository>L.L.Horn Collection</repository>
                  <collection></collection>
                  <idno></idno>
               </msIdentifier>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
      </encodingDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <front>
         <note></note>
      </front>
      <body>
         <opener>
            <!-- groups dateline,
               byline, salutation -->
            <dateline>
               <placeName></placeName>
               <date when="1990-05"></date>
            </dateline>
            <salute>Dear Friends and Colleagues, </salute>
         </opener>
         <!-- I am curious if all the paragraphs should be designed with lines or not-->
         <!-- It is our intention to add notes to different sections of the document, we just havent gotten to this one yet-->
         <p>Thank you very much for your expressions of concern and
            encouragement. After 35 days of treatment, I was discharge
            from the hospital on February 21 and returned to work at
            city hall on March 1. </p>
           <p>
              When shot, I thought my stay in this world was over.
              The subsequent operation was successful, but I felt for
              several days that I was treading the fine line between life
              and death. I am still recovering from the mental and
              physical shock of the attack -- an event which s hould never
              have occurred in this city of peace Nagasaki. It is at
              least a comfort to know that no one e lse was injured.
           </p>
         <p>
            The greatest encouragement for me was the many cordial
            messages of sympathy received during the weeks after ~ he
            incident. It is my firm intention now as mayor of Nagasaki
            to strive with you for nuclear disarma ment, for world peace ,
            and for genuine d e mocracy in Japan.
         </p>
         <p>
            The first thing that entered my mind on my hospital bed
            ,was the suffering of the ill, of the aged and handicapped,
            of the mentally distressed, and of single mothers. Watching
            the slow but steady growth of early spring leaves from the
            window, I realized clearly that we must persevere in the
            face of various circumstances in life.
         </p>
         <p>
            The faith passed on from my ancestors helped me to
            remain calm after the bullet passed through my chest, and to
            pray quietly to God. I am living now with peace and a
            feeling of enormous gratitude.
            Please accept my repeated thanks and my warm wishes for
            good health and happiness for you and your loved ones.

         </p>
         <p>
            Please accept my repeated thanks and my warm wishes for
            good health and happiness for you and your loved ones.

         </p>
         <closer>
            <!-- groups together
               salute and signed -->
            <salute>
               Sincerely, yours
            </salute>
            <signed>
               Hitoshi Motoshima
               Mayor of Nagasaki
            </signed>
         </closer>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
